The culprit
（灼(あらた)）犯人は―
just stood here and watched.
ただ―
じっと見ていた
The rain is over.
（炯(けい)）雨はやんだ
Arata, the rain is over.
灼 雨はやんだ
（灼）あ…
I'm finally sure
of the culprit's modus operandi.
やっと確信できた 犯人の手口が
Analyst Karanomori contacted me earlier.
先ほど 唐之杜(からのもり)分析官から
連絡があった
The data was just as we predicted.
例のデータ
俺たちの予想どおりだった
Now we know his method and his motive.
これで手段と動機 両方つかめた
We're going to arrest
Rick's murderer, Kei.
リックさんを殺した犯人
捕まえるよ 炯
Yeah.
ああ
Draw the knives
locked behind your eyelids.
♪～
Reap the lives that grow into shackles.
Even the lost memories that flee
once they're liberated and banished
Are an everlasting cubism.
Cause I know that in a future gone mad,
Even nightmares are peaceful.
RESET, RESET, yeah.
The midnight sun awakens
and turns to a riot.
A gun for a faux-friendly kiss.
A knife for a faux-revolutionary hug.
Get rid of it all, even the frozen chains.
Reality is always outside your head.
In a world seen through bestial eyes,
There is neither darkness nor light.
Draw the knives
locked behind your eyelids.
Reap the lives that grow into shackles.
Even the false memories that flash before
your eyes impatiently and impulsively
Are an everlasting cubism.
～♪
#02
Teumessian Sacrifices
The cause of this crash
（灼）今回の
墜落事故の原因は―
was the coincidental simultaneous
occurrence of 17 separate errors.
17項目にも及ぶ
複合的なミスが―
偶然にも重なり発生しました
There were 78 personnel,
including mechanics, on board.
整備士など関係者は延べ78人
There was no issue with any of their Hues.
色相に問題のあった人はゼロ
So it was an accident, right?
（天馬(てんま)）だから事故なんだろ？
Consider this: If you want to harm someone
while keeping your Psycho-Pass stable,
（灼）こう考えてください
人に危害を加えて なお
サイコパスを安定させたいなら―
it's best that you don't know
what you're doing.
自分が何をしているか
知らないのが一番です
The responsibility is distributed,
and no one knows everything.
大勢が事故原因の一部を担い
誰も全体像を知らない
So, no one's Hue is clouded.
だから誰の色相も曇らない
Are you serious?
（入江(いりえ)）ちょっと
それ 本気で言ってんすか？
At least someone would have
to know everything in a murder.
（天馬）殺す気なら最低１人は
全部 分かってるでしょう
How come their Hue's unaffected?
何で そいつの色相は
無事なんです？
There was no guarantee he'd die.
（灼）死ぬとはかぎりませんから
（天馬）あん？
If Rick had stayed in his seat,
he'd have escaped the crash.
リックさんが席にとどまれば
事故を免れていたんです
In that case, his kit malfunction would
have frightened him, clouding his Hue.
その場合 キットの不具合などで
恐怖が増幅され―
色相は曇ったでしょう
Death or Psycho-Pass deterioration.
（志恩(しおん)）死か サイコパスの悪化か
The culprit offered him a choice.
選択の余地はあった
And it was the victim who chose.
選んだのは あくまで被害者
Whoever planned the crash
didn't have a direct hand in his death.
事故を設計した誰かが
手を下したわけじゃない
So, their Hue didn't cloud.
だから その誰かは色相が曇らない
Many people unknowingly complicit.
Just like those account books.
大勢が加担し
自覚がないって点は―
例の帳簿と一緒ね
So they were embezzling, after all?
やっぱ会社の金をくすねてたのか？
It's not that simple.
（雛河(ひなかわ)）そう単純じゃない
Rick really was a genius.
死んだリックさん 本当に天才
He figured it out himself.
１人で解明してた
What he found
その内容は―
was a nation-wide scam modeled on
a financial system from the old era.
旧世紀の金融システムを模倣した
国家規模の詐欺だ
A scam? They're just mortgages, right?
（入江）詐欺？
ただの住宅ローンでしょ？
フッ
I had Hinakawa make a holo
to assist my explanation.
分かりやすく説明するため―
雛河さんに
ホロを作っていただきました
Let's say Todoroki takes out
a loan at the bank
まず廿六木(とどろき)さんが
銀行でローンを組み―
and buys a house from a housing firm.
住宅会社から
家を買ったとします
Interest
So I'm a home-owner now?
（天馬）俺が家持ちかよ
The house appreciates in value,
so Todoroki sells it.
（灼）廿六木さんは すぐ
家が値上がりしたので売りました
But I just bought that!
おい 買ったばっかだろ
He pays off the loan with the profit.
もうかったお金でローンを完済
He takes out another loan
and buys a more expensive house.
またローンを組んで
もっと高い家が買えました
Since he made a profit,
he buys two this time.
もうかったので
今度は２軒 買いました
For real?
（天馬）マジか
Kisaragi sees this and follows suit,
hoping to make money.
（灼）それを見た如月(きさらぎ)さんが―
同じようにもうけようと
家を買います
But her income is substandard,
so she has a high interest rate.
（炯）ただし―
収入が基準以下のため
金利が高く設定された
Because they don't know
if I can pay it back?
（如月）借金を返せるか
分からないから？
Correct. The higher the risk,
the higher the interest.
そうだ リスクが高いものほど
金利は高くなる
And even Irie, the least well-off,
can get a loan thanks to subprime lending.
そして
最も貧乏な入江さんでも―
ローンが組めるようにしたのが
サブプライムです
Subprime
（入江アバター）うっ
What's subprime lending?
“サブプライム”って何だ？
A type of high-interest mortgage targeted
at low-income groups a long time ago.
大昔に存在した―
低所得層向けの
高金利住宅ローンだ
This allowed people at all income levels
to buy and sell houses.
これにより あらゆる人間が
住宅売買を盛んに行った
Then,
そして…
the banks consolidated these mortgages
into financial instruments.
銀行は多数の住宅ローンをまとめて
金融商品にした
They sold them to investment companies,
making a profit while transferring risks.
それを投資会社に売ることで―
利益を得ながら
リスクを肩代わりさせた
A credit rating agency assessed
these securities to be trustworthy.
（灼）この証券を
信用できると評価したのが―
格付け会社です
With the highest trust rating,
I can make a tidy profit off of them.
（志恩）最高評価で
信頼性もあるし―
これは大もうけできちゃうわね
And so, the housing market expanded
and more money changed hands.
（炯）こうして住宅市場が拡大し
動く金が増大した
The more you make, the more you want.
（志恩）もうかれば
もうかるほど欲しくなるのよね
Let's blow it up even more.
（灼）では もっと増やしましょう
How many houses do you plan to buy?
（天馬）えっ 何軒 買う気だよ
Now, what's wrong with this picture?
（灼）何かおかしいと思いません？
Why do loans to wealthy and poor people
have the same rating?
何で金持ちと貧乏人のローンが
同じ評価なんだ？
Weren't they high-interest, high-risk?
リスクが高いから
金利が高いんじゃなかったのか？
Are they being intimidated?
（天馬）脅されてんのかよ
Housing prices should rise.
This should be fine.
（雛河アバター）
住宅は値上がりするはず
だから これでいいはず
うっ！　くっ…
"Should"?
（如月）“はず”って…
That's a load of bull!
（天馬）ウソ八百じゃねえか
But everyone believed this fantasy,
averting their eyes from the truth,
（灼）でも みんなが幻想を信じ
真実から目をそらすことで―
because the bubble created
massive profits.
バブルによる莫大な利益が
生まれていった
And then, the bubble burst.
そしてバブルは崩壊した
Millions of people lost their savings,
their homes, and their jobs,
（炯）こうして何百万人もが
貯金も家も仕事も失い―
and the world economy took a huge hit.
世界経済は大打撃を受けた
Sasagawa and Yonehara recreated this
in our Sibyl society.
（灼）些々河(ささがわ)と与根原(よねはら)は―
シビュラ社会で
これを再現したんです
They used the anti-isolation policy
to stage a housing bubble.
開国政策を利用し
住宅バブルを演出
They remade the illegal
real-estate securities into stocks,
ご法度の不動産金融商品を
株式などで作り替え―
and got ministries and banks to sell them.
省庁や銀行に売らせました
Knowing it would collapse, they planned it
so they alone would make massive profits.
いずれ破たんすると知りながら―
自分たちだけが莫大な利益を得る
仕組みを作ったんだ
This is what Rick wanted
to blow the whistle on.
リックさんが告発したかったのは
これです
In the end, citizens and immigrants
would be left holding the bill.
最後にツケを払うのは
国民と入国者たち
They'd all be deep in debt.
みんな借金まみれになる
No one would know
what they were complicit in.
誰も何に加担してるか分からない
It's a system from the old era
that sparked global conflict.
世界紛争の火種にもなった
旧世紀のシステム
120-percent illegal.
120％(パー) 違法よ
But it will be tough to investigate.
（雛河）ただ捜査は難しいです
Huh? Why?
はあ？　何でよ？
Just enforce the pair of them.
２人とも執行すりゃいいでしょ
Their Psycho-Passes are clear.
連中のサイコパスに問題はない
All we have on them
are illegally obtained ledgers.
手札は
不正に持ち出された帳簿のみ
We lack evidence.
立証困難だ
So you're saying we can't do anything?
じゃあ 何もできないと？
No, not necessarily.
いえ そうとはかぎりません
Leak it to audit agencies?
（霜月(しもつき)）監査機関へ リーク？
Many agencies must have noticed the rise
（炯）多くの機関が
宅地の値上がりや―
in housing prices
and sudden changes in stock prices.
急激な株価の変動に
気づいているはずです
Submit our evaluation of the data Rick
left us with the bureau chief's approval.
リックさんが残したデータの
評価報告を―
局長許可の下 送らせてください
They'll slip up if they hear we found out.
俺たちが暴いたと分かれば
尻尾を出します
That's overly optimistic.
（霜月）楽観的すぎる
If they claim the data was falsified
and we fail to prove otherwise,
データは捏造(ねつぞう)だと言われて
証明に失敗したら？
you'll have committed
a serious breach of regulations.
あなたたちが深刻な規定違反を
犯したことになる
I'll take responsibility.
俺の責任です
No, we will.
“俺たちの”です
ハァ…
You think the buck will stop with you?
あなたたちのクビで済む問題？
OK, let's do it.
（霜月）オーケー やりましょう
Thank you, ma'am.
（炯･灼）ありがとうございます
（与根原のおびえ声）
Calm down, Yonehara.
（些々河）落ち着け 与根原
But it's an audit.
（与根原）か… 監査だぞ
Public Safety got the data.
Didn't you take care of it?
（与根原）
データが公安に渡ったんだ
始末したんじゃなかったのか？
I've taken all possible precautions.
なしうる対処は すべて講じた
It was your mismanagement
that got us into this situation.
そもそも お前の管理ミスが
招いたことだぞ
You're saying it's my fault?
えっ お… 俺のせいだってのかよ！
Consolidate the assets.
財産をまとめろ
If we transfer to a Dejima firm
using my Foreign Affairs connections,
総務省のコネを使い
出島(でじま)の会社に移籍すれば―
Public Safety won't get to us easily.
公安も簡単には手は出せん
My Psycho-Pass...
（与根原）サイコパスが―
is deteriorating.
悪化してるんだ
（泣き声）
Don't lose your head.
しっかりしろ
We've done a good thing.
俺たちは いいことをしたんだ
We've given people bonuses and homes.
大勢にボーナスと家を与えた
That dead accountant
and those who have gone bankrupt
死んだ会計士も
破産する連中も―
are sheep who couldn't understand
how society works.
社会の仕組みを
理解できん羊どもだ
You can't blame us foxes
for preying on them.
俺たち狐の責任じゃない
I don't have your mental toughness.
（与根原）俺は お前みたいな
メンタル･タフネスじゃないんだよ
There's no evidence I was involved.
（些々河）この件に
俺が関与した証拠はない
Wha...?!
（与根原）ちょっ…
I sent you an address.
住所を送った
Go there. They'll take care of the rest.
そこに行け
あとは そいつらが動いてくれる
（携帯電話のバイブ音）
そこに行け
あとは そいつらが動いてくれる
No.
嫌だ… 嫌だ
No, please stop.
やめてくれよ 頼むよ
I'm begging you.
Don't leave me!
お… 置いてかないでくれよ
Sasagawa!
些々河！　うう…
Macroeconomics was invented
（些々河）人は
罪悪感から逃れるため―
so people wouldn't have to look
their sacrifices in the eye.
生けにえの顔を見ずに済む
マクロ経済を発明した
But I'm different.
だが俺は違う
I can sacrifice anyone whenever I want.
いつでも誰かを犠牲にできる
（与根原）ううっ
Goodbye.
じゃあな
（泣き声）
Psycho-Pass exceeding permissible values
measured in Minato.
（アナウンス）港(みなと)区にて
規定値超過のサイコパスを計測
（サイレン）
Proceed to the scene immediately.
直ちに現場へ急行してください
（サイレン）
Well, no wonder he'd run.
（天馬）まあ そりゃ逃げるわな
Man, talk about a bad loser.
（入江）ったく
往生際が悪(わり)い野郎だ
Takumi Yonehara's Psycho-Pass confirmed.
（コミッサ）
与根原 巧(たくみ)のサイコパスを確認
En route to street-scanner
undeployed district.
街灯スキャナー
未配備地区へ移動中
What about Sasagawa?
He's the mastermind, right?
些々河は？　彼が主犯ですよね？
No response on the scanners.
He's still clear.
（雛河）スキャナーは無反応
クリアなまま
I'll have Karanomori find him.
（灼）唐之杜さんに
捜してもらいます
Yonehara comes first. We'll pursue him.
（炯）与根原が先だ 追うぞ
Mr. Sasagawa told me everything.
（沼倉(ぬまくら)）些々河さんから
話は聞いてる
Sounds like you've had it rough.
大変だったねえ 心配しなさんな
Don't worry. We'll bring you
somewhere Public Safety won't go.
公安が来ないところに
ちゃんと送ってやるから
All ready, Boss.
（構成員）親分 準備できました
Good. Take him.
（沼倉）おう 連れてってやんな
Here we are, buddy.
（構成員）ここだぜ 兄ちゃん
We can't use our Dominators past here.
これ以上は
ドミネーターが使えない
Until the relay drones are up,
中継ドローンを配置するまで―
don't take any risks.
むちゃはダメだよ
Got it. You be careful, too.
（炯）分かってる
お前も気をつけろ
See if anyone's spotted Yonehara.
与根原を見た者がいないか捜そう
No one here is gonna talk.
（天馬）ここの連中が
しゃべるわけないでしょ
I have an idea.
（入江）心当たり ありますよ
Hey, Irie.
おい 入江
There's an old gangster named Numakura
who runs this place.
ここらを仕切ってる
沼倉って悪のじいさんがいる
A rich guy on the run would go to him.
金持ちが逃げ込むなら そこだ
Can you take us to him?
案内できるか？
His place is just down this street.
（入江）
この通りのすぐ先がヤサです
All right, let's go.
（炯）よし 行くぞ
You and your big mouth.
（天馬）余計なこと教えんなよ
（入江）ヘッ
We might need more cable.
ケーブルが足りないかも
Why not wait for the Public Safety drones
and use wireless relays?
公安局ドローンの到着を待って
無線で中継しては？
We don't have time to wait.
待ってる時間はないんです
We need to arrest Yonehara
safely and quickly.
早く与根原さんを
無事に捕まえてあげなきゃ
"Safely"...?
（如月）無事って…
You two, please carry the relay drone
to the prescribed location.
お二人は予定地点まで
中継ドローンを運んでください
And you, Inspector?
監視官は どこへ？
I'll hook up the cable.
ケーブルは俺がつなげます
Wow.
すごい
Who the hell are you?
（構成員）何だ？　てめえら
Public Safety Bureau.
Surrender Takumi Yonehara.
公安局だ
与根原 巧を渡せ
Refuse, and we'll take enforcement
action and search.
拒否すれば執行のうえ
ここを捜索する
You can't enforce squat
in this neighborhood.
（沼倉）こんな界わいで
執行も何もねえでしょ
Bluffing won't get you anywhere.
はったり かましても
効き目はねえよ
Get out.
帰んな
The guy you want left on a trip.
捜し人は旅に出ちまったよ
Now get lost, pigs.
（構成員）さっさと帰れ ポリ公
Stand aside.
（炯）そこをどけ
（構成員）あ？
うっ うおっ
（構成員たちのどよめき）
（構成員）やりやがったな こら！
You'll pay for that!
フッ
（構成員）うおー！
Hey, now.
おいおい
Screw you!
（構成員）クソが！
うおっ ぐっ！　うう…
ああ！
（天馬）ふっ！
（構成員）ぐわ！
Never mess with your elders.
おっさんをナメんな
（構成員）ああっ
（構成員）うおっ ぐわあ！
（銃声）
Eat lead!
死ねや おら！
（銃声）
（炯）うっ
Kei!
炯！
Come and get me, if you can!
来るなら来てみろ おら
I'll fill you full of holes!
蜂の巣にしてやる
うわっ
うう… うっ
（炯）ふっ！
（沼倉）ううっ
（沼倉）うっ うう…
Crime Coefficient is over 300.
（ドミネーター）
犯罪係数 オーバー300
Enforcement mode is Lethal Eliminator.
執行モード
リーサル エリミネーター
Take careful aim and eliminate the target.
慎重に照準を定め
対象を排除してください
Get out of our country, immigrant!
この国から入国者は出ていけ！
うっ！　ぐわあー！
Looks like they meant to sell him
in pieces.
（天馬）あ～ バラ売りする
つもりだったな こりゃ
Plenty of people still prefer people
to pigs, after all.
（入江）今でも
豚より人がいいってやつは―
わんさかいるからな
Kei, Karanomori just found Sasagawa.
炯 さっき唐之杜さんが
些々河を見つけた
We have to inform him
of what's happened to his friend.
友人がどうなったか
教えてやらないとな
You found Yonehara?
（霜月）与根原を見つけたわね？
Dead on arrival.
We're about to pursue Sasagawa.
（炯）到着時 死亡
今から些々河を追います
Your mission is complete.
Leave the rest to me.
任務は完了 あとは私に任せなさい
You're letting Sasagawa go?
（灼）些々河を逃がす気ですか？
If you want an explanation, come back.
説明が欲しければ戻りなさい
（通信が切れた音）
（霜月）あっ
Huh? The call dropped.
あれ？　切れちゃった
It's hard to get a signal here.
ここ 通信環境 悪いね
That's unfortunate.
しかたないな
We'll carry out the mission.
任務遂行に専念するぞ
You pair of morons!
う… このクソバカコンビ！
Didn't you have them in hand?
（花城(はなしろ)）
手綱は握っていたはずでは？
（霜月）んっ！　すぐに止める
手を出さないで！
I'll stop them. Stay out of it.
Action is our motto.
（花城）行動こそ
私たちのモットー
If you value your men, pull them out.
部下がかわいければ
引かせなさい
Who would value them?
（霜月）んん！
かわいいわけあるか！
I guess this is goodbye to Tokyo.
東京も しばらく見納めか
（サイレン）
Stand by here. Understood?
お前たちは ここで待機だ
いいな？
"Stand by"?
待機って…
They're really going to ignore
the chief's orders?
課長命令 本当に無視する気だ
Sticking their necks out for one scumbag?
悪党１人にクビ懸けるつもりか？
If they're serious,
they've got a few screws loose.
マジなら相当ネジ外れてるぜ
Kisaragi, Hinakawa, wait here.
如月と雛河は おとなしく待ってな
Hey, he said to stand by.
We can all wait here.
ちょっと
待機って言われたんだから
待ってればいいのよ
Don't sweat it.
（入江）大丈夫 大丈夫
（灼･炯）あっ
Public Safety Bureau!
公安局です！
Make way!
そこをどいて！
And if we refuse?
（宜野座(ぎのざ)）“嫌だ”と言ったら？
We'll make you move!
どかすだけだ！
うっ
A prosthetic hand?
義手か
Everyone, stop right there.
（狡噛(こうがみ)）全員 そこで止まれ
I told you to stand by!
待機と言ったろう
Seems you've got your hands full.
てこずってんじゃないすか
We'll show you the ropes, Inspector.
手本をお見せしますよ 監視官
うっ
（殴る音）
（天馬）ううっ うお！
うう…
Dammit!
（入江）クソが
あっ
That's enough.
そこまでにしておけ
Please don't move.
（灼）動かないでください
Error. Target is a Special Investigator
（ドミネーター）エラー
対象は外務省 行動課 特別捜査官
for the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
Operations Department.
Permission required
to identify Crime Coefficient.
犯罪係数の特定には
許可が必要です
- The trigger will be locked.
- Foreign Affairs?
えっ 外務省… 行動課？
So, you didn't let Sasagawa get away.
些々河を逃がした… わけじゃない
Yeah, that's right.
ああ そのとおりだ
（電子音）
Bring me a mental kit.
（些々河）
メンタルキットを持ってきてくれ
あっ
You're persistent, Detective.
しつこい刑事だ
My Hue won't cloud. You can't arrest me.
俺の色相は曇らない
お前たちに捕まえられるものか
I'm afraid I'm not interested in your Hue.
（須郷(すごう)）残念だが
お前の色相に興味はない
What?
何だと？
We're from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
Operations Department.
（花城）我々は外務省 行動課よ
Frederica Hanashiro
You're wasting your time.
You can't uncover a thing!
無駄なことを
お前らごときに
何一つ解明できはしない
Enough chit-chat.
御託は結構
Put him to sleep.
眠らせて
Ginoza, we've secured the target.
宜野座 獲物を確保したわ
Roger that.
（宜野座）了解だ
We've arrested Sasagawa.
些々河は俺たちが捕らえた
Don't worry.
He can't escape punishment now.
もう犯罪逃れはできないから
安心しろ
（雛河）あっ
フッ
The domestic cases are yours.
国内の事案は任せたぞ
What's this?
（灼）これは…
There are other foxes.
狐は他にもいる
Creatures that keep escaping the hounds.
猟犬から逃れ続ける存在が
ん…
Long time no see, Inspector.
（宜野座）久しぶりだな 監視官
"Inspector"?
Was that a jab at me?
監視官なんて呼び方して 嫌み？
That wasn't my intention.
そのつもりはないんだが…
Now we're even!
これで貸し借りなし！
国内は私たちの縄張りよ
Internal matters are our turf.
Tell that horrible blonde that.
そう あのいけ好かない金髪に
伝えて
Why not tell her yourself?
自分で話せばいいだろう
I can't stand her guts!
（霜月）
いけ好かないって言ったでしょ
And I'm still sore over her
poaching my capable officers!
優秀な人間を引き抜かれて
腹立ってんの
Capable?
優秀？
It's a figure of speech!
あっ… 言葉のあやよ！
You're a latent criminal! Don't act cocky!
潜在犯のくせに
いい気にならないで
I'll pass the message along to my chief.
こっちの課長には俺から伝える
Hey, have you seen Akane?
ねえ 先輩には会ったの？
There's no need to.
（宜野座）その必要はない
I know what I should be doing for her.
あの人のために
俺が何をなすべきかは分かってる
You morons!
このクソバカども！
I told you to come back!
戻れと言ったでしょうが！
Well, the call was dropped and...
えっと…
通信が切れてしまいまして
Who were those two?
あの２人 何者ですか？
Foreign Affairs, Operations Department.
Nobuchika Ginoza and Shinya Kogami.
外務省 行動課
宜野座伸元(のぶちか) 狡噛慎也(しんや)
Both formerly Unit One.
両方 元一係よ
Unit One?
元一係…
The Dejima firm Sasagawa tried to escape
to was one of their trap corporations.
（霜月）些々河が逃げようとした
出島の会社は―
行動課のトラップ企業
They'd been investigating
the Transport Company for a while.
かなり前から あいつらは
トランスポート社を捜査してたのよ
And if you want to stay inspectors,
それと 監視官でいたいのなら―
obey your bosses' orders
上司の指示に…
and the interests of the system.
システムの利益に従いなさい
What have we here? A business trip?
（梓澤(あずさわ)）あーあ これは出張かな？
You're too close. And annoying.
（小畑(おばた)）近い うざい
What a truly amusing pair.
本当に面白い２人だ
Relation over.
（ラウンドロビン）
リレーション オーバー
Congressman, please display the results.
コングレスマンは
リゾルツを表明してください
So, one inspector has fallen into
the hands of the Operations Department.
（代銀(しろがね)）インスペクター１名が
行動課の手に落ちたか
I'm impressed that Shizuka predicted it.
これを読んだ静火(しずか)君は
大したもんだ
You mean that this is Roundrobin's will
（裁園寺(さいおんじ)）これが
ラウンドロビンの意志であり―
and essential to Bifrost's security?
私たちビフロストの安泰に
不可欠だったと？
The collapse of the subprime diagram
and Operations' trap were self-evident.
（静火）サブプライム･
ダイヤグラムの崩壊も―
行動課のトラップも自明
That's all.
それだけです
A sacrifice was necessary
to spring the trap
（代銀）誰かを生けにえにして
トラップをあぶり出し―
and reset the diagram.
ダイヤグラムを
組み直す必要があった
All is for Bifrost.
（裁園寺）
すべてはビフロストのため
Sacrificing an inspector is a small price.
インスペクターの犠牲など
安いもの
Well done.
お見事
Results confirmed.
（ラウンドロビン）
リゾルツ確認 配当を実行
Apportioning dividends.
You're the next dealer.
I look forward to it, Shizuka.
（代銀）君が次の親だ
楽しみだよ 静火君
The pleasure is mine.
こちらこそ
フン
We finally made a breakthrough.
（花城）ようやく突破口が開けた
You could say that these results
この成果は やはり彼女の…
were the end result
of Akane Tsunemori's actions.
常守(つねもり) 朱(あかね)の行動が
我々を導いたと言っていい
Let's not talk about her.
その話は やめましょう
She'll receive her fair judgment one day.
彼女もいずれ正当な裁きを受ける
That's what she wants.
それが彼女の望みよ
And you want to hunt foxes in Japan.
As promised, I'll leave you to it.
あなたの望みは国内の狐狩り
約束どおり お任せするわ
気をつけてね
Take care.
Don't worry. I'll see it through.
心配無用 必ず成し遂げる
Please do.
（花城）頼んだわ
ふう…
That's all I can tell you.
（炯）話せるのは以上です
Your husband was
a courageous whistleblower.
ご主人の内部告発は
勇気あるものでした
A credit to immigrants.
入国者の誇りです
Thank you very much.
（アーディレ）
ありがとうございます
Also, Rick's application was approved.
（灼）それと
リックさんが出した申請―
通りました
You can live in this country from now on.
この先ずっと
この国で暮らせますよ
（アーディレ）
ああ… 何とお礼を言ったら…
How can I thank you?
It was Sibyl's decision.
シビュラの判断です
Your Japanese name has been registered.
あなたの和名も登録済みだ
You are not compelled to use it,
and you may change it at any time.
無理に使う必要もないし
いつでも変えられる
My Japanese name?
和名… 何という名ですか？
What is it?
Kaori.
（炯）“香(かおり)”
（アーディレ）あ…
I think it's a nice name.
I can feel Rick's love for you in it.
いい名前だと思うな
リックさんの愛情を感じる
Yes.
（アーディレ）はい
All right, I solved it.
よし 解けた
Let's go.
（灼）行こう
（炯）ああ
Yeah.
あっ
Rick...
あなた…
Adele, I've made a decision.
（リック）アーディレ
俺は ある決意をした
勝手にすまない
I'm sorry I was selfish.
I'm recording this
because I have something to tell you.
君に伝えたいことがあって
これを残す
I will always love you.
いつまでも君を愛している
We've finally found a clue.
やっと手がかりが見つかった
Tetsuya Sasagawa
That's the first step.
それが最初の一歩だ
（ピアノの音）
I will find the truth,
（灼）必ず真実を見つけてみせる
Dad.
父さん
Aspersions Cast on Minister of Welfare
Atsushi Shindo
Have some tea, dear.
（舞子(まいこ)）あなた お茶よ
Thank you.
（炯）ありがとう
I will see this through to the end,
最後まで やり遂げてみせるよ
Akira.
兄さん
I got it.
（朱）受け取ってる
うん
I await your next report.
次の報告を待ってるわ
Yes, help them both.
ええ ２人を助けてあげて
Thank you, Hinakawa.
ありがとう 雛河君
I am currently awaiting a judgment
that could begin at any moment.
（朱）私は今―
いつ始まるか分からない
裁きを待つ身だ
But that also means that I've been
liberated from this society.
だが それゆえに この社会から
初めて解放されたとも言える
The truth of our society
will finally come to light.
やがて判明するであろう
この社会の真実
What will people believe when it does?
その時―
人は何を信じるのだろうか…
（金属をひっかく音）
（灼）ん…
ふう…
ああ…
（ゲップ）
With Governor Koriyama out of favor,
new candidates are stepping up.
（リポーター）
郡山(こおりやま)都知事が任期を終え―
次の候補者が出そろいました
There's a great turnout
at the election parade.
選挙パレードは
大変な盛り上がりです
Kosuke Yakushiji
Kosuke Yakushiji, independent,
endorsed by the Eugenics Party.
（放送）薬師寺(やくしじ)康介(こうすけ)
無所属 優生党(ゆうせいとう)推薦
Karina Komiya
（選挙カーの音楽）
Karina Komiya, independent,
endorsed by the Affirmation Party.
（放送）小宮(こみや)カリナ
無所属 肯定党(こうていとう)推薦
（土谷(つちや)）ううっ
I have to protect her.
（土谷）彼女を守らねば
I...
（カリナ）私は…
...can't go on like this.
（スポーツ選手）
このままだと危ないですね
All my fans...
（カリナ）ファンのみんな…
I doubt you'll get out unscathed.
（コメンテーター）
無事じゃ済まないと思いますよ
This calls for drastic measures.
何か抜本的な対策を…
On the contrary...
それどころか…
You'll be erased.
（キャスター）消されますね
It's only a matter of time.
（コメンテーター）
時間の問題でしょう
（土谷）あっ
The Hues of the hotel staff who found
the body have deteriorated.
（志恩）転落した死体を見つけた
ホテルスタッフの色相が悪化
（サイレン）
We're still identifying the victim.
被害者の身元は現在 照会中よ
Understood.
了解です 到着しだい
現場のケアを行います
We'll perform on-site care on arrival.
Bodies like that are the worst.
They're all gooey.
あの手の死体は最悪だぜ
ぐっちゃぐちゃで
You might hurl, Inspector.
監視官様 吐いちゃうんじゃない？
Don't worry. I'll be fine.
（灼）大丈夫ですよ ご心配なく
What is this, The Inugami Murders?
犬神家(いぬがみけ)かよ
What's that?
何ですか？　それ
The body matches a guest.
Room's also been identified.
（炯）宿泊者に該当あり
部屋も特定できた
The victim is Kojo Tsuchiya, age 61.
（コミッサ）
被害者は土谷荒城(こうじょう) 61歳
Former professor of neuroscience
at Toto College of Science.
元東都(とうと)理科大学 教授
専門は脳科学
Receiving psychological treatment here
due to Hue deterioration.
色相悪化のため
当施設でメンタル治療中
At a high-class hotel like this?
こんな高級ホテルで治療？
It's more relaxing than a hospital.
病院より
リラックスできるんですよ
Care only the rich can experience, huh?
金持ちにしか味わえねえケアか
His Hue deteriorated despite
the treatment, so he killed himself.
（天馬）治療のかいなく
色相悪化を苦にして自殺
Case closed. Time to leave.
はい 終わり 撤収 撤収
But still,
（灼）でも まあ―
now that we're here,
we may as well go over his room, too.
せっかくですから
彼がいた部屋も調べてみましょうよ
Fine.
へいへい
あん？
What are you doing?
（入江）何やってんすか？
Two people.
（灼）人数は２人
Judging by their footprints,
both over 180 cm tall,
足跡からして
どちらも身長180センチ以上
and at least 100 kg.
体重100キロ以上
Bodyguards who had enhancement surgeries?
強化手術を施した
ボディーガードか
Most likely.
恐らくね
OK.
はーい
Stop, little crime labs.
鑑識君たち 止まって～ フフッ
How obedient and adorable.
素直でかわいい
Yeah, obedient. Unlike us.
俺たちは素直じゃねえからな
（入江）ヘッ
あっ
んっ
Why do you think he threw it out?
どうして捨てたんだと思う？
Maybe he dropped it?
（炯）落としたんじゃないのか？
It's practically a necessity.
He'd look for it if he dropped it.
（灼）ないと不便だし
落としたら捜すでしょ
It wouldn't be hard to find here.
見つかりにくい場所でもないし
（炯）うん…
The TV's broken.
（灼）テレビは壊れてる
He must've thrown a bottle
or something at it.
（炯）ボトルか何かを
投げつけたらしいな
These are almost certainly
Dr. Tsuchiya's fingerprints.
十中八九 土谷博士の指紋だろう
He tried to open the window.
（灼）窓を開けようとしたみたい
He must have known it wouldn't open.
開かないと分かってるはずなのに
He was trying to jump from the window.
窓から飛び降りようとした
Or he was trying to leave the room.
あるいは部屋から出ようとした
うーん
Let me take a dive.
ちょっと潜ってみる
There's a good chance this was a suicide.
Don't go too deep.
自殺者の可能性大だ
潜りすぎるな
I know.
分かってる
（ノイズ）
It's raining.
（灼）雨が降ってる
No. Concentrate.
（灼）違う 集中しろ
Focus on Dr. Kojo Tsuchiya.
土谷荒城博士に
What are they doing?
何やってんだ？　あいつら
Did seeing the body cloud their Hues?
死体見て
色相 曇ったんじゃない？
ん…
Analyzing
（天馬･入江）ん？
（天馬）何だ？　こりゃあ
What's going on?
（土谷）うっ！　くっ くう…
んっ！
うっ う… ああ…
（土谷の力み声）
ああ…
（手をたたく音）
The rain is over.
（炯）雨はやんだ
Arata, the rain is over.
灼 雨はやんだ
あ…
It went back.
戻りやがった
（ノイズ）
（入江）いよいよ いかれてるぜ
He's finally lost it.
He fell from there.
（灼）あそこで落ちた
うわ！　あっ
Huh?
あれ？
You idiot!
（炯）このバカ！
That scared me.
（灼）ああ… びっくりした
That's my line!
（炯）こっちのセリフだ！
（灼）ハハッ
He was headed for the lift climber?
（炯）リフトクライマーに
向かっていたのか
He tried to contact someone,
but his device was offline.
誰かと連絡を取ろうとしたけど
デバイスはオフラインだった
There were guards outside.
外には見張りがいた
Maybe he was confined
under the pretext of Hue improvement.
色相改善の名目で
監禁されていたのかもな
So he tried to get out somehow,
で 何とか外へ出ようとして―
then, Inugami Murders?
犬神家
If there had been water in the pool,
he'd have had a slight chance of survival.
（炯）プールに
水が張ってあれば―
僅かだが
生存の可能性はあったな
It happened to be under construction.
（灼）たまたま工事中だった
The door and TV also malfunctioned,
fanning his fears.
ドアもテレビも不具合が起きて―
恐怖をあおった
That window happened to come loose.
あの窓も たまたま外れた
A chain of malfunctions.
Like the transport drone crash.
（炯）不具合の連鎖…
輸送機の事故と似てるな
The guy behind that got arrested, right?
Even if Foreign Affairs got him.
こないだの犯人
あれ 捕まったでしょ
外務省に連れてかれちまったけど
"There are other foxes."
狐は他にもいる
Hm... That's bugging me,
like a needle stuck in my throat.
んー 引っかかる
喉に針が刺さったみたい
Then let's look until you're satisfied.
なら 納得いくまでやろう
Dr. Tsuchiya.
（志恩）土谷博士
He was on idol and gubernatorial candidate
Karina Komiya's psychological care staff.
都知事選に立候補した
アイドル政治家―
小宮カリナの
メンタルケアスタッフだったようね
He was care staff, but he was receiving
treatment for his own Hue deterioration?
ケアスタッフなのに
自分の色相が悪化して治療中だった
He must've had a rough job.
（志恩）
いろいろ大変なんじゃない？
Komiya's agency paid all his hotel bills.
ホテルの支払いは
すべて小宮の事務所持ち
They even built the doctor a lab
inside the agency.
あと事務所内に博士のラボまで
作ってもらってるわね
We'll have to speak with that idol, then.
そのアイドルさんと
お話ししないとですね
Then there's one more person to talk to:
Kosuke "Heracles" Yakushiji.
なら もう１人にも話を聞こう
（炯）薬師寺･ヘラクレス･康介に
（天馬）ん…
Who's Heracles?
（灼）ヘラクレスさんって誰？
Don't you watch the news?
（炯）ニュースくらい見ろ
You don't know Yakushiji?
（天馬）薬師寺を知らねえとは―
That's our bean sprout of an inspector
for you.
さすが もやしみてえな
監視官様ですねえ
Bean sprouts are full of nutrients.
もやしは栄養たっぷりですよ
I bet you've never had them.
食ったことないだろ お前
I'll show you a good restaurant.
うまい店 教えましょっか？
Probably a place in the slums,
knowing you.
お前な… どうせスラムの店だろ
Really? I can't wait!
へえ～ 教えてくださいよ
Anyway, Heracles is his old ring name.
He's a strong contender for governor.
ともかく ヘラクレスは
昔のリングネームで―
都知事の有力候補者だ
He's vying with Komiya for the top spot.
小宮カリナとトップを争ってる
I'll leave Heracles to you, then, Kei.
じゃ そのヘラクレスさんは
炯に任せるね
Got it. I'll let you out up ahead.
（炯）分かった
この先で降ろすぞ
Don't look at me
（スピーカーから流れる
「FIRE BURNING WOMAN」）
Like you've made up your mind
About who I am.
I want to smile more.
Throw away my tears.
FIRE BURNING WOMAN!
Stand up now.
This era will change me.
Wow, she's cute.
へえ～ かわいい
She's sure got glitz and glamor.
キラッキラしてんねえ
Karina Komiya. Became an entertainer
at age 4, following Sibyl's determination.
小宮カリナ
シビュラ判定に従い
４歳で芸能界入り
When she was 9, her parents divorced
from disputes over fee management.
９歳の時
ギャランティー管理を巡り―
争っていた両親が離婚
She had it rough.
苦労してるな
It happens all the time.
よくある話でしょ
She changed agencies at age 12.
12歳で事務所移籍
She joined the Sibyl-authorized idol group
Existence.
シビュラ公認
アイドルグループ―
“イグジステンス”に
所属するも―
However, the other members became
latent criminals and the group disbanded.
他のメンバーが
色相悪化で潜在犯に
グループ解散
She went solo at 17.
17歳で独立
She succeeded as a pop star,
fashion leader, and mental celebrity.
ポップスター
ファッションリーダー
メンタルカリスマとして成功
After winning an Asia Grammy Award
for "FIRE BURNING WOMAN," she retired.
代表曲
「FIRE BURNING WOMAN」で―
アジアグラミー賞を受賞後
引退を表明
She became a politician at her peak,
saying she was obeying Sibyl suitability.
人気絶頂で政治家に転身
“シビュラ適正に従った”と
コメント
Why did she want to be a politician?
政治家になって何する気だろう？
Well, they're mostly figureheads,
まあ 大抵 お飾りだが―
but debating policy with Sibyl
is still the work of politicians.
シビュラが審議する政策協議は
今も政治家の仕事だ
They can do more than you'd think.
真面目にやりゃあ
意外と やることあります
You know about politicians, too?
政治家にも詳しいんですか？
A lot of them end up
in the slums, you know.
多いんすよ スラム落ちする連中
Your vehicle has arrived.
車両が到着しました
（入江）クッ フフフッ
Still, all but the frontwoman became
latent criminals? What's with that?
にしても センター以外 潜在犯って
面白くないすか？
They could've gone down together.
みんなで夢追って奈落の底
You've got bad taste, huh, Irie?
入江さん 趣味悪いんですね
Maybe it's my upbringing.
育ちのせいですかね？
Aren't you going to drive?
…って 運転しないんですか？
I have a license,
but would you mind driving for me?
（灼）免許は持ってますよ
でも よかったら
運転してもらえませんか？
I'm an enforcer.
（入江）俺は執行官だぜ
Is there a problem?
何か問題あります？
あ…
People say fierce competition
leads to Hue deterioration,
（天馬）激しい競争は―
色相を悪化させるなんて
言われがちだが―
but Sibyl recognizes
the utility of sports.
シビュラは
スポーツの有用性を認めてる
A good game clears the Hues of players
and spectators alike.
すばらしい試合は―
選手と観客の色相を
同時にクリアにするってな
The Human Vs. Mechanics Championship,
H.V.M.
ヒューマン ＶＳ(バーサス)
メカニクス･チャンピオンシップ
“Ｈ･Ｖ･Ｍ”
A Sibyl-approved combat sport
limited to robot opponents, huh?
対ロボット限定の
シビュラ認可の格闘技か
（ゴング）
The athletes dope
at pharmaceutical companies,
アスリートは
製薬会社の下でドーピングし―
and produce children
based on genetic determination.
遺伝子判定に従い 子供を作る
Yakushiji's a prime example.
薬師寺は その代表格でさ
He's a genetic elite who'd win gold
in every event if the Olympics came back.
もしオリンピックが
復活したら―
全種目 金メダルの
遺伝子エリートだ
（ゴング）
That was a splendid match!
（薬師寺）すばらしい試合だった！
A healthy mind dwells in a healthy body.
健全な精神は健全な肉体に宿る
The Sibyl System proves that
through our Hues.
シビュラシステムは
色相で それを証明してくれる
Everyone in this arena already knows
who's the best choice
この会場にいる皆様は
誰が次の都知事にふさわしいか―
to be the next governor, am I right?
もう ご存じでしょう！
To be a Heracles!
トゥー ビー ア ヘラクレス！
（観客たちの歓声）
To be a Heracles!
（観客たち）
トゥー ビー ア ヘラクレス！
To be a Heracles!
トゥー ビー ア…
I'm Karina Komiya.
（カリナ）小宮カリナです
Are you a real detective?
本物の刑事さんですか？
I've played one on TV, but this
is my first time seeing the real thing.
私 ドラマで
演じたことがありますけど―
本物を見るの初めてなんです
I'm a little nervous.
何だか緊張します
I'm the one who's nervous.
俺こそ緊張しちゃいます
What is the Public Safety Bureau's
business?
（オワニー）公安局の方々が
何のご用ですか？
You know Dr. Kojo Tsuchiya, don't you?
（灼）土谷荒城博士
ご存じですね？
Everyone at the agency relied on him
as part of our psychological care staff.
（カリナ）
メンタルケアスタッフとして―
事務所のみんなが
頼りにしていました
I'm sad he's gone.
悲しいです
Could it have been suicide,
like they said on the news?
（オワニー）
ニュースで言ってるように
自殺の可能性があるんですか？
We aren't sure.
Was there some sort of trouble?
それが よく分からないんです
何かトラブルとか
ありませんでしたか？
Well...
あの…
No, forget I asked that.
（灼）いや 今のなしで
（オワニー）え？
Huh?
If there was, you wouldn't tell me, right?
あったら正直には言いませんよね
I can tell you.
言えます
えっ
Although Dr. Tsuchiya was very skilled,
he ended up stalking me.
（カリナ）土谷博士は
優秀な方でしたが―
私のストーカーみたいに
なっていたところがあって
As a result, his Hue became unsuitable.
それで色相が
思わしくなかったんです
A stalker, huh?
ストーカーね…
Cute girls always have to deal
with them, don't they?
かわいい子には
付き物ですね ストーカー
Is that supposed to be a compliment?
それ 褒めてるんでしょうか？
It was thanks to Komiya's kindness that
we received Tsuchiya's expensive care.
土谷のために
高額なケアを用意したのは―
小宮の優しさなんです
Yeah, I thought so.
うんうん ですよねえ
I'm sorry, but we're busy with
the election. We can't take more time.
（オワニー）申し訳ありませんが
都知事選で忙しく これ以上は
Yes, thank you for your cooperation.
ええ
ご協力ありがとうございました
Oh, may we look at Dr. Tsuchiya's lab?
あっ 土谷博士のラボ
拝見していいですか？
Yes. I'll have someone take you there.
（オワニー）はい 案内させます
Now if you'll excuse me, detective.
それでは刑事さん 失礼します
Good luck, Karina!
カリナちゃん 頑張って！
Thank you!
ありがとう！
Thanks for your support!
カリナの応援 よろしくね
ハァ… 何だかな
I don't know about this.
She's quite scary.
（灼）怖い人ですね
（入江）え？
She only talked to me,
and didn't even glance at you, Irie.
俺とだけ話して
入江さんは見ようともしなかった
And she always said "detective,"
not "detectives."
呼ぶ時も“刑事さんたち”じゃなく
“刑事さん”って
So she won't even talk
to a latent criminal?
潜在犯にゃ触れるのも嫌ってか
I never said anything
about you being an enforcer.
入江さんが執行官だなんて
ひと言も言ってませんよ
（入江）あっ
She'd never seen a detective.
（灼）刑事は初めて見る
If that's true, she saw one of us was
a latent criminal without prior knowledge.
それが本当なら 予備知識なしで
片方が潜在犯だと見抜いた
All her band mates became latent
criminals, but she alone stayed clear.
仲間全員が潜在犯になっても
自分１人 クリアでい続けた
It's not just strength of will.
She has Mentalist talent.
意志の強さだけじゃない
メンタリストの才能がある
ん…
If she were a criminal...
もし犯罪者なら…
She'd be a menace.
手ごわい相手です
♪～
Stupid perfection in your own castle
How smart. You cause me to yawn
Look,
The key to the door is in your hand
Don't you let anyone take control
What do you want?
Go get it. Play by your own rule
The winner always controls the game
You stand in your belief
There's no promising future
Always helpless
Crying for the moon
Finger trembles in fear
With the weight of the trigger
There's a way for us
Show them how we fight
Pull the trigger
～♪
"Psycho-Pass" refers to the measurement
of a person's mind and personality.
This is a work of fiction. Any resemblance
to real persons or groups is coincidental.